University of Connecticut 1998.0185
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
University of Connecticut, President's Office Records [Albert N. Jorgensen, 1935-1962]
undated, 1935-1962.
1998.0185
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
16.0 Linear feet
When Connecticut State College became the University of Connecticut in 1939, the new laws and By-laws stated that, “the President of the University is the executive and administrative officer of the Board [of Trustees]. In this capacity he is responsible for the operations of the University and is given authority requisite to that end.” This is the mandate under which President Jorgensen worked throughout his long service as President of the University. The President was also designated as “chairman of the University Senate and of the several schools and colleges.” ” The administrative reorganization authorized by President Jorgensen for the University in 1939 placed direct responsibility for the schools and colleges. President Jorgensen was thus able to devote all his energies chiefly to the fulfillment of his plans for the overall development of the University.
University of Connecticut. President's Office.
Biography
Like some of his predecessors, Albert Nels Jorgensen was born and educated in the Midwest, where the tradition of land-grant higher education his historically strong. He attended Coe College in Iowa and took a Ph.D. in Educational Administration at Eastern Michigan College and at the University of Buffalo, he did important scholarly work in the field of educational measurement and evaluation. In 1935, at the relatively young age of 36, he was appointed the seventh president of Connecticut State College, succeeding Charles C. McCracken.
Despite the hard economic circumstance of those times, Dr. Jorgensen brought to this office a far-sighted vision of a great public institution at Storrs. He immediately launched a vigorous campaign to persuade state agencies and civic organizations of the value of the College to the state, and of its need for more adequate support. In 1938, he presented an ambitions long-range plan for the physical development of the College, asking 23 million dollars from an historically resistant state legislature for the construction of a library, dormitories, and other needed facilities. In justifying his request, Dr. Joegensen pointed to the 31% increase in enrollment since he had taken office in 1935. Due in part to the President's persuasiveness and prestige, and in part to the changing climate of opinion, he was able to win support for his building program. The progress made by the institution in Dr. Jorgensen's first years was ratified by the changing of its name to the University of Connecticut in 1939. The Wilbur L. Cross Library, and impressive symbol of the institution's new status, was also built in 1939. President Jorgensen succeeded in maintaining his program for the physical development of the University during World War II by taking advantage of federal funds available through New Deal programs, although some major projects had to be put off because of wartime shortages of materials.
When the nation returned to peacetime, its colleges and universities were faced with the formidable task of meeting the demands for higher education made by the wave of veterans returning with the new GI Bill in hand. Under the imaginative leadership of President Jorgensen, the University of Connecticut became a leader in this work, establishing new University branches in Hartford, Waterbury and Fort Trumbull (New London), and increasing its enrollment from 1200 in 1939 to more than 7500 by 1947. While the effects of the veterans' wave were still being felt, other important needs in the University's physical plant were filled. President Jorgensen, a strong proponent of college athletics, vastly improved the University's facilities with the construction of the Physical Education Building in 1950, and its later addition, and Memorial Stadium in 1953. The North Campus dormitories relieved a great shortage of housing in 1950, and the long-awaited Student Union opened in 1953.
While the needs for the physical development of the campus might have been most pressing, and the accomplishments in this area most evident, President Jorgensen was equally concerned with maintaining and upgrading the quality of the University's academic programs. The most important academic changes during his administration were in the development and strengthening of graduate work and research. The Graduate School was founded in 1940, and the University awarded its first Ph.D. in 1949. By the end of the Jorgensen era in 1962, doctoral programs were being offered in more than sixty fields. In another measure of the improvement in the academic standing of the institution, there was but one national honorary society represented on the campus in 1935. By 1960, the Silver Anniversary of the Jorgensen Presidency, twenty-six national honorary societies had established chapters at the University, including Phi Beta Kappa in 1956.
President Jorgensen also helped the University of Connecticut to establish a strong reputation as a defender of academic freedom. He insisted as a prerequisite for his acceptance of the position her in 1935 that the Trustees suspend a rule prohibiting discussion of the issue of compulsory military training on the campus. During World War II he defended the right to due process of a member of the University staff of foreign origin who was accused of disloyal acts. He also resisted outside pressure to dismiss a staff member who had come under suspicion during the McCarthy era.
During the last decade of his administration, President Jorgensen continued the development of the University and the advancement of its academic standards. New academic buildings and dormitories were built to meet the steadily increasing enrollment. New University branches were opened in Stamford and Torrington. The University also began to build an enviable reputation as a center for research financed by grants from the federal government and private foundations. The campus' social and cultural life was enhanced by the opening of Jorgensen Auditorium in 1956, which has brought numerous fine artistic productions to the campus in years since.
Dr. Jorgensen retired in 1962 after 27 years in office, one of the longest tenures of any American university president. His years of service as President are coincided with the rise of the University of Connecticut from a small, even obscure, college of 800 students to the great public institution that it is today. He is perhaps best remembered as the architect of the University campus. Most of the permanent buildings on the campus today are monuments to the energy, ability and vision of President Jorgensen. But he was more than just a “bricks and mortar man.” As President Glenn W. Ferguson said at the passing of Dr. Jorgensen in 1978, he was also “a 'builder' in the philosophical sense; a champion of academic freedom, a person who recognized that excellence is the critical quest for a university, who created this university from a state college, and who built an institution that cared about its future and cared about that quest for excellence.”
Scope and Content
These records consist of the general correspondence of Albert N. Jorgensen, who was President of the University of Connecticut from 1935 to 1962. The correspondence is arranged alphabetically by topic within each academic year in one series. Because some of the Jorgensen papers were apparently inadvertently destroyed before they reached the University Archvies, there is correspondence missing for the years 1942-1943, 1943-1944, 1945-1946, 1946-1947, and 1951-1952.
Arrangement
The Free Speech Issue concerns the Trustees statement forbidding students from public agitation or discussion of military training on campus. This subseries contains letter, telegrams, and petitions addressed to Jorgensen, his predecessor President McCracken, Trustee Arthur Greene, the Governor Wilbur Cross.
Regulations and Policies contains a number of administrative policy statements of President Jorgensen's tenure ranging from teaching loads to athletics to grievances. This subseries supplements the policy statements found in Series I; it is not complete in itself. The material is arranged alphabetically by topic.
75th Anniversary contains some of the correspondence, planning documents and programs associated with the 1956-1957 celebration of the University's 75th anniversary.
Jorgensen Speeches delivered by the President are arranged chronologically by date of delivery. This subseries includes many convocation and commencement addresses.
Series I: Correspondence ( 1935-1962 )folder titles generally refer to the subject of the correspondence or to the individual or agency with whom the correspondence is concerned.
Series II: Subject Files ( 1935-1962 ) are further subdivided by topic: Free Speech Issue (1935), Regulations and Policies (1935-1962), the 75th Anniversary (1956-1957), and Speeches (1935-1959). This series constitutes a later addition to the records.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
The records of President Albert N. Jorgensen (1935-62) were stored in Gulley Hall until 1962, when they were moved to the attic of Beach Hall. During the time they were there, some of the Jorgensen papers apparently were inadvertently destroyed.
Acquisition Information
In 1968, the records were brought to the Special Collections Department of the Wilbur Cross Library. They were transferred to the Historical Manuscripts and Archives Division of the University of Connecticut Library in August 1979, and were arranged and described in the summer of 1980. Materials filed in Series II were received between 1983 and 1985.
Jorgenson, Albert N. (Albert Nels), 1899-1978.; Administrative Records.; Administrator.; Bylaws.; College presidents—Connecticut.; Correspondence.; Financial Records.; Notes.; Photocopies.; Press releases.; Speeches.; Universities and colleges—Administration.; University of Connecticut. Office of the President.; University of Connecticut—History.; University of Connecticut—Presidents.
- Series I: Correspondence, 1935-1962
  - Undated, 1935-1962 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - 1935-1936
    - A (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - Agricultural buildings - plans (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - B (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - Bi - Brn (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Bressler, R. G. (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - Bro - Bz (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - Bureau of Biological Survey (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - Butterfield, Ernest W. (Box 1:, Folder 9)
    - Ca - Cn (Box 1:, Folder 10)
    - Co - Cz (Box 1:, Folder 11)
    - D (Box 1:, Folder 12)
    - Dadourian, H. N. (Mrs.) (Box 1:, Folder 13)
    - Davis, Irving G. (Box 1:, Folder 14)
    - Dodge, Richard E. (Box 1:, Folder 15)
    - Dole, Summer A. (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - E (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - Edel, Walter L. (Box 1:, Folder 18)
    - Ellis, Benjamin W. (Box 1:, Folder 19)
    - F (Box 1:, Folder 20)
    - Faculty activity records (A - C) (Box 1:, Folder 21)
    - Faculty activity records (D - H) (Box 1:, Folder 22)
    - Faculty activity records (J - N) (Box 1:, Folder 23)
    - Faculty activity records (P - Y) (Box 1:, Folder 24)
    - French, Mildred P. (Box 1:, Folder 25)
    - Ga - Gn (Box 1:, Folder 26)
    - Gentry, Charles B. (Box 1:, Folder 27)
    - Greene, H.A. (Box 1:, Folder 28)
    - Guyer, Roy J. (Box 1:, Folder 29)
    - Ha - Hd (Box 1:, Folder 30)
    - Hall, Edward F. (Box 1:, Folder 31)
    - He - Hn (Box 1:, Folder 32)
    - Hicks Fund (Box 1:, Folder 33)
    - Ho - Hz (Box 1:, Folder 34)
    - Hollister, Sherman P. (Box 1:, Folder 35)
    - Honorary Recognition, 1935 (Box 1:, Folder 36)
    - Hook, James W. (Box 1:, Folder 37)
    - Hypes, James L. (Box 1:, Folder 38)
    - I (Box 1:, Folder 39)
    - Inauguration - commemorative volume (Box 1:, Folder 40)
    - Inauguration - correspondence and programs, 1935-1936 (Box 1:, Folder 41)
    - Inauguration - mailing lists (Box 1:, Folder 42)
    - Income tax material (Box 1:, Folder 43)
    - Inspection of buildings (Box 1:, Folder 44)
    - J (Box 1:, Folder 45)
    - Jorgensen, Albert N. (Box 1:, Folder 46)
    - K (Box 1:, Folder 47)
    - Li - Lz (Box 1:, Folder 48)
    - Land Grant College Association (Box 1:, Folder 49)
    - Longley, Raymond I. (Box 1:, Folder 50)
    - Ma - Md (Box 1:, Folder 51)
    - Me - Mn (Box 1:, Folder 52)
    - Mo - Mz (Box 1:, Folder 53)
    - N (Box 1:, Folder 54)
    - N.E.C.C.I.A. (Box 1:, Folder 55)
    - O (Box 1:, Folder 56)
    - Oliver, Bernard J. (Box 1:, Folder 57)
    - Pa - Ph (Box 1:, Folder 58)
    - Pi - Pz (Box 1:, Folder 59)
    - Ra - Rn (Box 1:, Folder 60)
    - Religious education (Box 1:, Folder 61)
    - Ro - Rz (Box 1:, Folder 62)
    - Sa - Sd (Box 1:, Folder 63)
    - Salary schedule (Box 1:, Folder 64)
    - Se - Sm (Box 1:, Folder 65)
    - Slate, William L. (Box 1:, Folder 66)
    - Sn - Sth (Box 1:, Folder 67)
    - Sti - Sz (Box 1:, Folder 68)
    - T (Box 1:, Folder 69)
    - Van Bibber, George (Box 1:, Folder 70)
    - Wa - Wg (Box 1:, Folder 71)
    - Waugh, Albert E. (Box 1:, Folder 72)
    - Wh - Wz (Box 1:, Folder 73)
    - White, George C. (Box 1:, Folder 74)
  - 1936-1937
    - A (Box 1:, Folder 75)
    - Alsop, Joseph W. (Box 1:, Folder 76)
    - American Council on Education (Box 1:, Folder 77)
    - Attorney General (Box 1:, Folder 78)
    - B (Box 1:, Folder 79)
    - Bennett, Charles J. (Box 1:, Folder 80)
    - Bi - Brn, 1936-1937 (Box 1:, Folder 81)
    - Biennial budget material (Box 1:, Folder 82)
    - Biological survey (Box 1:, Folder 83)
    - Bro - Bz (Box 1:, Folder 84)
    - Buckley, John (Box 1:, Folder 85)
    - Buildings (Box 1:, Folder 86)
    - Butterfield, Ernest W. (Box 1:, Folder 87)
    - Ca - Cn (Box 1:, Folder 88)
    - Co - Cz (Box 1:, Folder 89)
    - College studies (Box 1:, Folder 90)
    - Commencement Committee (Box 1:, Folder 91)
    - Cross, Wilbur L. (Box 1:, Folder 92)
    - D (Box 1:, Folder 93)
    - Dadourian, H.M. (Mrs.) (Box 1:, Folder 94)
    - Davis, I.G. (Box 1:, Folder 95)
    - Department of Education (Box 1:, Folder 96)
    - Desmond, Thomas H. (Box 1:, Folder 97)
    - Dole, Sumner A. (Box 1:, Folder 98)
    - E (Box 2:, Folder 1)
    - Edel, Walter L. (Box 2:, Folder 2)
    - Ellis, Benjamin W. (Box 2:, Folder 3)
    - Engineering (Box 2:, Folder 4)
    - Engineering - appropriation for buildings (Box 2:, Folder 5)
    - Faculty request for sabbaticals (Box 2:, Folder 6)
    - Farm and Home Week Committee (Box 2:, Folder 7)
    - Fenton, Horace J. (Box 2:, Folder 8)
    - French, Mildred P. (Box 2:, Folder 9)
    - General Assembly (Box 2:, Folder 10)
    - Gentry, C.B. (Box 2:, Folder 11)
    - Graduate Study Committee (Box 2:, Folder 12)
    - H (Box 2:, Folder 13)
    - Hook, James W. (Box 2:, Folder 14)
    - Iowa, State University of (Box 2:, Folder 15)
    - J (Box 2:, Folder 16)
    - Jorgensen, A.N. - personal (Box 2:, Folder 17)
    - King, Olcott F. (Box 2:, Folder 18)
    - Kirkpatrick, W.F. (Box 2:, Folder 19)
    - L (Box 2:, Folder 20)
    - Legislature (Box 2:, Folder 21)
    - Letters of congratulation (Box 2:, Folder 22)
    - Longley, R.I. (Box 2:, Folder 23)
    - M (Box 2:, Folder 24)
    - Military science (Box 2:, Folder 25)
    - O, 1936-1937 (Box 2:, Folder 26)
    - P (Box 2:, Folder 27)
    - Ratcliffe Hicks Scholarship (Box 2:, Folder 28)
    - Registrar (Box 2:, Folder 29)
    - S (Box 2:, Folder 30)
    - Salary study (Box 2:, Folder 31)
    - Se - Sm (Box 2:, Folder 32)
    - Slate, William L. (Box 2:, Folder 33)
    - Soil conservation program (Box 2:, Folder 34)
    - Spencer, Samuel R. (Box 2:, Folder 35)
    - Summer program (Box 2:, Folder 36)
    - T (Box 2:, Folder 37)
    - Van Bibber, George (Box 2:, Folder 38)
    - Vegetable Garden Committee (Box 2:, Folder 39)
    - W (Box 2:, Folder 40)
    - White, G.C. (Box 2:, Folder 41)
    - Wood, Walter C. (Box 2:, Folder 42)
    - W.P.A. projects (Box 2:, Folder 43)
    - Y (Box 2:, Folder 44)
  - 1937-1938
    - A (Box 2:, Folder 45)
    - Alumni Association (Box 2:, Folder 46)
    - Association of American Universities (Box 2:, Folder 47)
    - Attorney General (Box 2:, Folder 48)
    - Bi - Brn (Box 2:, Folder 49)
    - Biological survey (Box 2:, Folder 50)
    - Bookstore Committee (Box 2:, Folder 51)
    - Bro - Bz (Box 2:, Folder 52)
    - Budget director (Box 2:, Folder 53)
    - Butterfield, E.W. (Box 2:, Folder 54)
    - Ca - Cn (Box 2:, Folder 55)
    - Commencement Committee (Box 2:, Folder 56)
    - Corbett, Roger B. (Box 2:, Folder 57)
    - Cross, Wilbur L. (Box 2:, Folder 58)
    - D (Box 2:, Folder 59)
    - Davis, Irving G. (Box 2:, Folder 60)
    - Desmond, Thomas H. (Box 2:, Folder 61)
    - Dole, Sumner A. (Box 2:, Folder 62)
    - Edel, Walter L. (Box 2:, Folder 63)
    - F (Box 2:, Folder 64)
    - Faculty Residential Committee (Box 2:, Folder 65)
    - Faculty training and experience, 1937-1938 (Box 2:, Folder 66)
    - Farm and Home Week Committee (Box 2:, Folder 67)
    - Gentry, Charles B. (Box 2:, Folder 68)
    - Gerbereich, J.R. (Box 2:, Folder 69)
    - Gilman, Ralph L. (Box 2:, Folder 70)
    - Greene, Harry A. (Dr.) (Box 2:, Folder 71)
    - Hall, Edward F. (Box 2:, Folder 72)
    - Hicks Scholarship (Box 2:, Folder 73)
    - He - Hn (Box 2:, Folder 74)
    - Hollister, Sherman P. (Box 2:, Folder 75)
    - J (Box 2:, Folder 76)
    - Jorgensen, A. N. (Box 2:, Folder 77)
    - K (Box 2:, Folder 78)
    - Land Grant College Association (Box 2:, Folder 79)
    - Honorary Recognition (Box 2:, Folder 80)
    - Ho - Hz (Box 2:, Folder 81)
    - Hypes, James L. (Box 2:, Folder 82)
    - Longley, Raymond I. (Box 2:, Folder 83)
    - Mo - Mz (Box 2:, Folder 84)
    - N (Box 2:, Folder 85)
    - O (Box 2:, Folder 86)
    - Oliver, B.J. (Box 2:, Folder 87)
    - Personnel director (Box 2:, Folder 88)
    - Pi - Pz (Box 2:, Folder 89)
    - Public works commissioner (Box 2:, Folder 90)
    - Ra - Rn (Box 2:, Folder 91)
    - Radio program (Box 2:, Folder 92)
    - Registrar (Box 2:, Folder 93)
    - Rodent control (Box 2:, Folder 94)
    - Sabbatical leave (Box 2:, Folder 95)
    - Scholarship Loan Committee (Box 2:, Folder 96)
    - Slate, William L. (Box 2:, Folder 97)
    - Standardization Committee (Box 2:, Folder 98)
    - Sti - Sz (Box 2:, Folder 99)
    - T (Box 2:, Folder 100)
    - Wa - Wg (Box 2:, Folder 101)
    - White, George C. (Box 2:, Folder 102)
  - 1938-1939
    - A (Box 2:, Folder 103)
    - Agricultural Council (Box 2:, Folder 104)
    - American Council on Education (Box 2:, Folder 105)
    - Attorney General's Office, 1938-1939 (Box 2:, Folder 106)
    - Baldwin, Raymond E. (Box 2:, Folder 107)
    - Bro - Bz (Box 2:, Folder 108)
    - Budget director (Box 2:, Folder 109)
    - Budget requests (Box 2:, Folder 110)
    - Co - Cz (Box 2:, Folder 111)
    - Corbett, Roger B. (Box 2:, Folder 112)
    - Cross, Wilbur L. (Box 2:, Folder 113)
    - Dormitory campaign (Box 2:, Folder 114)
    - Edel, Walter L. (Box 2:, Folder 115)
    - F (Box 2:, Folder 116)
    - Faculty training and experience (Box 2:, Folder 117)
    - Gentry, Charles B. (Box 2:, Folder 118)
    - Go - Gz (Box 2:, Folder 119)
    - Grace, A. G. (Box 2:, Folder 120)
    - Ha - Hd (Box 2:, Folder 121)
    - Hall, Edward F. (Box 2:, Folder 122)
    - Hicks Scholarship (Box 2:, Folder 123)
    - Ho - Hz (Box 2:, Folder 124)
    - Honorary Recognition (Box 2:, Folder 125)
    - Hurricane damage (Box 2:, Folder 126)
    - Hypes, James L. (Box 2:, Folder 127)
    - Jorgensen A. N. (Box 2:, Folder 128)
    - Income tax - state employees (Box 2:, Folder 129)
    - K (Box 2:, Folder 130)
    - La - Lh (Box 2:, Folder 131)
    - Land Grant College Association (Box 2:, Folder 132)
    - Legislative material (Box 3:, Folder 1)
    - Longley, Raymond I. (Box 3:, Folder 2)
    - Military correspondence (Box 3:, Folder 3)
    - N (Box 3:, Folder 4)
    - New London Junior College (Box 3:, Folder 5)
    - News bulletin (Box 3:, Folder 6)
    - O (Box 3:, Folder 7)
    - Personnel director (Box 3:, Folder 8)
    - Pre - payment hospitalization plan; correspondence and notes (Box 3:, Folder 9)
    - Pre - payment hospitalization; minutes of Governor's committee, 1938 September - December (Box 3:, Folder 10)
    - Pre - payment hospitalization plan; reports from other states (Box 3:, Folder 11)
    - Pre - payment hospitalization plan; reports of Governor's Committee on Pre - Payment Hospitalization (Box 3:, Folder 12)
    - Public Works commissioner (Box 3:, Folder 13)
    - Public works department - library equipment (Box 3:, Folder 14)
    - Ra - Rn, 1938-1939 (Box 3:, Folder 15)
    - Regional experiment station (Box 3:, Folder 16)
    - Registrar (Box 3:, Folder 17)
    - Religious education (Box 3:, Folder 18)
    - Sabbatical leave (Box 3:, Folder 19)
    - Scholarship Loan Committee (Box 3:, Folder 20)
    - Slate, William L. (Box 3:, Folder 21)
    - Soliciting agents (Box 3:, Folder 22)
    - State universities (Box 3:, Folder 23)
    - Tax Research Institute of America reports (Box 3:, Folder 24)
    - Wa - Wg (Box 3:, Folder 25)
    - Wh - Wz (Box 3:, Folder 26)
    - White George C. (Box 3:, Folder 27)
  - 1939-1940
    - Aeronautical development commission - Harvey L. Williams, Chair (Box 3:, Folder 28)
    - Agricultural engineering, A program for the development of (Box 3:, Folder 29)
    - Alcorn, Paul (Box 3:, Folder 30)
    - Alsop, Joseph W. (Box 3:, Folder 31)
    - American Council on Education (Box 3:, Folder 32)
    - Attorney General (Box 3:, Folder 33)
    - Baldwin, Raymond E. (Governor) (Box 3:, Folder 34)
    - Bi - Brn (Box 3:, Folder 35)
    - Biennial report (Box 3:, Folder 36)
    - Bonds (Box 3:, Folder 37)
    - Buckley, John (Box 3:, Folder 38)
    - Budget (Box 3:, Folder 39)
    - Budget department (Box 3:, Folder 40)
    - Budget material (Box 3:, Folder 41)
    - Ca - Cn (Box 3:, Folder 42)
    - Civil Aeronautics Authority (Box 3:, Folder 43)
    - Co - Cz (Box 3:, Folder 44)
    - Comptroller, State (Box 3:, Folder 45)
    - Congress (Box 3:, Folder 46)
    - Corbett, Roger B. (Box 3:, Folder 47)
    - Dadourian, Ruth M. (Box 3:, Folder 48)
    - Development commission - Sidney A. Edwards (Box 3:, Folder 49)
    - Edel, Walter L. (Box 3:, Folder 50)
    - Education, State Department of (Box 3:, Folder 51)
    - F (Box 3:, Folder 52)
    - Faculty letters on reorganization (Box 3:, Folder 53)
    - Faculty training and experience (Box 3:, Folder 54)
    - Finance commissioner, 1939-1940 (Box 3:, Folder 55)
    - Financial report for 1938-1939 (Box 3:, Folder 56)
    - French, Mildred P. (Box 3:, Folder 57)
    - Functions of a state university (Box 3:, Folder 58)
    - Ga - Gn (Box 3:, Folder 59)
    - Gentry, Charles B. (Box 3:, Folder 60)
    - Go - Gz (Box 3:, Folder 61)
    - Graduate Study Committee (Box 3:, Folder 62)
    - H (Box 3:, Folder 63)
    - Hollister, George H. (Box 3:, Folder 64)
    - Honorary Recognition (Box 3:, Folder 65)
    - Hook, James W. (Box 3:, Folder 66)
    - Hypes, James L. (Box 3:, Folder 67)
    - Information for Board of Trustees (Box 3:, Folder 68)
    - J (Box 3:, Folder 69)
    - Jorgensen, A. N. (Box 3:, Folder 70)
    - King, Olcott F. (Box 3:, Folder 71)
    - L (Box 3:, Folder 72)
    - Land Grant Colleges, Association of (Box 3:, Folder 73)
    - Ledgebrook applicants (Box 3:, Folder 74)